Leo Brooks

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL BIO

I am a software engineer with fluency in MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, SQL, and Python. I work to build and refactor intuitive and efficient solutions for the complex problems of tomorrow. Through my experiences running a kitchen and building track cars, I've found passion in forging new paths. With my adeptness in mechanical, automotive, and computational engineering fundamentals, I strive toward a more efficient version of the world today.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Languages | ES6, HTML, CSS, Python
- Libraries & Frameworks | React, Node, Express, Django
- Database | PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM
- Other | RESTful, Routing, JSON

CONTACT INFORMATION

Mobile: (980)-425-0209 Email: Idbrooks297@gmail.com

Github: @ldb297 LinkedIn: @brooksld Location: Puyallup, WA

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly / Jan. 2021 to April 2021

- Full-stack software engineering immersive student built out multiple 4-11 day agile based full stack applications utilizing technologies including: simple DOM manipulation, custom built back end api's, passport authentication, Node/Express, Mongo/React, Django/Python.
- ~500 hours of experience.

Automotive Service Technician

Subaru of Puyallup / Nov. 2017 - Dec. 2020

- Stimulated team efficiency by implementing more productive methodologies while maintaining 100% accuracy of work.
- Advocated for the prioritization of customer investment value over gross profit to streamline customer satisfaction.
- Introduced daily quality assurance screenings to recognize and strengthen each other's weaknesses.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote Software Engineering Immersive Program

- Attended Jan. 2021 to April 2021
- Focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies

JSL 日本アカデミー

${\it Japanese Business/Language JLPT~N3}$

- Attended March 2015 to March 2016
- Graduated 99th percentile
- Remained in attendance after receiving certification as teaching assistant

PROJECTS

- Nutrifit | Django, Python, PostgreSQL
- Utilized USDA nutrition API to provide authenticated users a place to find and log nutritional statistics for daily meals.
- Nippon Runner | Node.js, React.js, Express.js, MongoDB
- Application built out to provide authenticated users a place to learn, practice, and refine hiragana reading skills.
- gamebook | Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL
- Provides authenticated users a place to search for video game titles and leave personalized comments on them with other users.
- [2B||!2B] | HTML5, CSS, ES6
- Battle simulation for users to attempt taking on various opponents.